Wasn't Sasahara-kun sleeping?
（フェッちゃん）
そういや 笹原(ささはら)君 寝てなかった？
（ウェボシー）
ああ 寝てた 寝てた
腕組んだまま ピクリともしないで
He definitely was!
He was crossing his arms and not moving an inch!
Misato, go wake him up!
みさと  起こしてきてあげなよ
（立花(たちばな)みさと）ええっ？
Sasahara-kun probably forgot that it's time to change classes.
（フェッちゃん）
次 教室移動だって
忘れてるんだよ 笹原君
Well, so what?
だ… だから 何だってのよ
ほっとけばいいでしょ
Just let him be.
That's not right.
かわいそうだよ
You guys are childhood friends.
（ウェボシー）
幼なじみなんでしょ？
行ってあげなさいよ
You should go wake him up!
And I think Sasahara-kun is alone in the room right now.
（フェッちゃん）それに 笹原君
今 きっと教室に一人だよ
Wha...
Well, I'm going ahead.
じゃあ 先行ってるね
Good luck!
（フェッちゃん）頑張ってね
ああ ちょっと　もう！
Hey!
Geez!
なんで私がこんなこと
してあげなきゃいけないのよ
Why do I have to do something like this?
Just because we're childhood friends...
幼なじみなんて関係…
Why don't you confess to Sasahara-san?
（立花みほし）
笹原さんに告白しちゃえよ
Sasahara!
笹原
Why are you sleeping when there's a classroom change?
あんた教室移動なのに
何 鮮やかに寝てんのよ
（笹原幸治郎(こうじろう)）
ああ　立花みさと？
Tachibana Misato?
と… とっとと
教科書 準備しなさいよ
Just get your textbooks ready!
That's right, I was just planning to rest my eyes.
（笹原）そうか
少し目を休ませていたつもりが―
It seems I went too far.
深く いざなわれていたと
いうわけか
早くしなさいって言ってんの
Hurry up already!
People might get weird ideas if we're late together!
一緒に遅れていったら
勘違いされるでしょ
Weird ideas?
勘違い？ 何がだ？
About what?
うっ うるさい
Shut up!
Nichijou 106
I didn't mean to!
ち… 違う
いや 違うっていうか
そこにあったっていうか
I mean, I didn't realise they were there!
It's because you weren't hurrying up!
大体 あんたが
サッサとしないから
Tachibana Misato.
（笹原）立花みさと
（みさと）あっ
Your hand is bleeding.
手　血が出ているぞ
What's with you being a nice guy?
なによ いい人ぶって
You should be angry at the fact that I broke your glasses.
私のケガより―
眼鏡 割れちゃったこと
怒ればいいじゃないの
No worries.
なーに  眼鏡は壊れても
痛くないが―
It doesn't hurt when my glasses are broken.
A hand injury does hurt, though.
手のケガは痛いからな
な… なにそれ
What do you mean?
Of course it hurts!
当たり前じゃない
ウマいこと言ったつもり？
You think you said something clever?
Besides, the other lens is still there.
幸い 片方のレンズが
残っているではないか
It's just like a warrior with a long history of service.
さながら歴戦の勇士ということか
That warrior is pretty frail.
（みさと）
その勇士の もろさたるや
Pretty frail.
もろさたるや
（笹原）あっ
（みさと）移動するよ
Let's go.
Tachibana.
（笹原）立花みさと
（みさと）分かってる
I know!
I already know that I'm at fault!
自分が悪かったことくらい
分かってるから
Walk or Don't
Actually, I don't think it's working out so well...
（男子生徒１）やっぱりさ
あれ イケてねえなって思うんだよ
Walk or Don't
（男子生徒１）だから…
（男子生徒２）うん？ あっ
Walk or Don't
That's right!
（女子生徒１）
そうなのよ　そしたら うん？
And then...
（女子生徒１）あ…
（女子生徒２）あ…
（みさと）ううっ 見られてる
They're looking at me!
I'm gonna die!
死ぬっ 死ぬっ
死ぬほど恥ずかしい
I'm gonna die!
I'm gonna die from embarrassment!
But I broke his glasses,
でも 眼鏡 壊したの私だし
私が笹原の目になんなきゃだし
so I need to become Sasahara's eyes.
It's all right!
大丈夫よ　大丈夫
If we just say he broke his glasses,
“こいつ眼鏡 壊れちゃって”って
言えば―
it'll look like I'm just helping out!
どっから どう見ても
慈善事業だし
そうよ ボランティア精神に
のっとって―
Yeah!
I'm getting in the volunteer spirit...
...and becoming your eyes for the day!
今日一日 あんたの目になるだけ
なんだからね
Tachibana Misato.
（笹原）立花みさと
Yes?
あっ はい！
Before we arrive at the classroom,
教室移動する前に
トイレに行っておきたいのだが
I would like to go to the restroom.
えっ？ ト… トイレって
Restroom?
You mean the men's restroom?
まさか男子トイレ？
（笹原）いかにも
That very one.
A sudden roadblock...
（みさと）いきなり障害が
But since it's my fault,
でも 私が悪いんだし
乗り越えてこそ深まるもんだし
I need to get over this block...
ううううっ
分かった　私も行く！
Got it!
I'll go in with you!
なぜだ？
Why?
Well, that's because your glasses are broken!
（みさと）だって あんた
眼鏡 壊れてるじゃない
And?
それが？
Geez. You're so thick-headed!
（みさと）もう 察しが悪いわね
Since you can't see anything, I'm becoming your eyes for the day!
目が見えないから―
今日一日 笹原の
目になってあげるって言ってるの
ああ　これはダテだ
These are just fakes.
What are you mistaking?!
何 勘違いしてんの
たまたま あんたの右腕にいた
小さな虫を―
I was just shooing off the bug that was pestering your arm!
手でおもむろに
圧迫していただけなんだからね！
Today is a beautiful day.
（ナレーター）本日は晴天なり
I-I know of a restaurant in Kamakura that has really hot curry!
（高崎(たかさき)先生）あっ あの
Curry
鎌倉にカレーが辛い店が
あるんですが
I see!
（桜井(さくらい)先生）あっ はい
How much spice can you tolerate when it comes to curry?
桜井先生は
何辛までいけますか？
Um, well...
え… えっと
Zero tolerance.
０(ゼロ)辛です
Same here!
ぼ… 僕もです
Nichijou 107
（長野原(ながのはら)みお）ああ
（相生祐子(あいおいゆうこ)）あっ
（東雲(しののめ)なの）あっ
Um, Naganohara-san...
（なの）あの長野原さん
そろそろ授業
Class is about to...
（みお）そろそろ授業
Hey, Mio-chan!
（祐子）
ちょ みおちゃん
ＬＬ教室そっちじゃないよ
Our next class isn't that way!
Our next class...
（みお）ＬＬ教室
And besides,
それに ほら あれだよ
you never know what's going to happen in baseball!
何が起こるの分からないのが
野球っつうか
That's what makes it fun!
それが楽しいっつうか
You never know what's going to happen in baseball.
（みお）
何が起こるか分からない
それが野球
Besides, you don't even know for sure that she's his girlfriend!
（祐子）
つうか まだ あの人が 彼女って
決まったわけじゃないっつうか
Hey, Nano-chan!
ねえ なのちゃん
What?
（なの）えっ？
あっ はい　そうですよ
Yes!
Of course!
Sasahara-senpai was...
（みお）笹原先輩が…
先輩が…
Senpai was...
Senpai...
先輩
Anyway, let's just go back!
（祐子）
とにかく戻ろうよ みおちゃん
Mio-chan!
（みお）はーん
（祐子）みおちゃーん！
Naganohara-san!
（なの）長野原さーん！
Nano-chan,
（祐子）
なのちゃんはＬＬ教室行って
先生ごまかしといて
get to the next class and somehow explain to the teacher!
（なの）あっ はい！
Got it!
Mio-chan, wait!
みおちゃん待て
（みお）ええーんっ
Mio-chan!
（祐子）みおちゃん　ぶつかる！
You're going to crash!
Mio-chan!
みおちゃーん！
（祐子）みおちゃん！
Mio-chan!
（みお）えーん
（祐子）みおちゃーん
Mio-chan!
（みお）うわーん
（祐子）みおちゃーん
M-Mio-chan!
（祐子）み… みおちゃん！
Mio-chan!
（祐子）みおちゃん！
（みお）ああーん
Mio-chan!
（祐子）みおちゃん！
（みお）うっ
M-Mio-chan!
（祐子）み… みおちゃーん
ちょ みおちゃん
Mio-chan...
（祐子）みおちゃん！
（見物人）おおっ
Mio-chan!
（祐子）みおちゃーん
（記者）じゃあ行きまーす
（祐子）みおちゃん
Mio-chan!
（シャッター音）
（祐子）みおちゃーん
Mio-chan!
This is my stop.
（おばあちゃん）降ります
いよっ
Mio-chan!
（祐子）みおちゃーん
M-Mio-chan...
（祐子）み… みおちゃん
M-Mio-chan!
み… みおちゃーん
Mio-chan!
（祐子）みおちゃーん
（祐子）
みおちゃん　みおちゃん
Mio-chan!
みおちゃん
みおちゃーん
Mio-chan!
みおちゃん みおちゃん
みおちゃん　みおー！
Damn it!
（みお）こなクソ！
Chan-mio!
（祐子）ちゃんみお！
（まーちゃん）パッ うっ プハッ
プハッ ハッ
うっ あっ ああっ
ハア ハアッ
（祐子）ちゃ… ちゃんみお！
Chan-mio!
（みお）ハア ハア ハア
（まーちゃん）ハア ハア ゴホッ
あ… ありがとう
T-Thanks...
（祐子）みおちゃん！
Mio-chan!
Mio-chan, are you all right?
みおちゃん  大丈夫？
（みお）ハア ハア
ハア…
I'm kinda...
なんか
...tired.
疲れちゃったよ
Mio-chan.
みおちゃん
Where is he?
（警官）どこだ？
（祐子）ああ？
Over here!
（おさむ）こっちです
Maa-chan!
（おさむ）あっ まーちゃん
（まーちゃん）おさむ
Osamu...
Thank god you're okay!
（警官）よかった 無事だったのか
Are you okay?
（おさむ）大丈夫？
（まーちゃん）うん なんとか
Somehow...
This person saved me...
この人が
助けてくれたから
（警官）おっ お前ら！
（祐子･みお）あっ！
You guys!
You're from that time...
（警官･祐子･みお）あのときの！
You know, that's known as obstruction of justice,
（警官）お前らなあ
あれは公務執行妨害といって―
and it's a serious crime!
れっきとした罪なんだぞ
Me, too?
お前らって 私も？
I would normally have to call the school...
本来なら
学校に連絡するところだけど…
Considering what just happened, I'll let it go.
まあ 今回のことに免じて
大目に見てやろう
ホントですか？
Really?
（紳士）おお いおった いおった
（祐子）あ？
Finally!
I finally found you, pig-tailed girl.
（紳士）ようやく見つかったわい
おさげの娘
I was surprised at your shadow boxing earlier.
さっきのシャドーを見て
ピーンときてな
Would you like to take on the world with boxing?
（紳士）どうじゃ？
ボクシングで
世界を取ってみんか？
（おばあちゃん）ひいっ
（おばあちゃん）ひったくり
（警官）うん？ あっ！
Don't think badly of me!
（ひったくり）悪く思うなよ
Well, I'm off now!
じゃあ 俺は行くから
Make sure to come to me later!
あとで署に来るんだぞ
表彰の日程とか教えるから
We need to fill out some stuff!
Onee-chan, I want you to have this.
（まーちゃん）
お姉ちゃん　これあげる
O-Okay.
Osamu, it's okay, right?
（まーちゃん）
おさむ　いいよな？
Of course!
（おさむ）もちろん
Anyway, after you calm down, drop by our gym.
（紳士）とりあえず
落ち着いたらジムに来なさい
We'll continue talking about it there.
話はそれからじゃ
I just noticed, but your English textbook is missing!
（祐子）
あっ みおちゃんの英語の教科書
いつの間にか なくなってる
フフフッ ウッフフッ
Mio-chan?
（祐子）みおちゃん？
Being rejected before even asking him out,
（みお）
告白する前にフラれたり
saving a child while on a full-out rampage,
全力疾走途中に
子どもを助けたり―
getting awards and medals,
表彰とか 凧(たこ)もらうとか
ボクサーにスカウトとか
and getting scouted as a boxer.
You really don't know what's going to happen.
ホント 何が起こるか分からない
It's exactly like you said, Yukko.
（みお）ゆっこの言うとおりだよ
（祐子）えっ？
Huh?
You really never know what's going to happen.
“何が起こるか分からない”
That's why it's interesting!
“だから面白い”
That's what baseball is, right?
“それが野球”ってね
What do you mean?
（祐子）えっ？ どゆこと？
（警官）うりゃ
See?
（みお）ほらね
Word Of The Day
I've realised that...
...fantasising is free.
（中村(なかむら)先生）
しまった　完全に見失った
Damn, I completely lost sight of her.
Nichijou 108
I was watching her ever since she left school,
学校から ピタリと
マークしていたんだが―
ふと 目を離した瞬間
いつの間にか消えていた
but as soon as I took my eyes off her,
she completely vanished...
What an amazing feature.
（中村）なんという高度な機能
It makes me want to find out your secrets even more.
ますます秘密を知りたくなったぞ
東雲なの
Shinonome Nano.
Well, since I've come this far,
さて ここまで来たんだ
それらしい家を探してみるか
should I see if I can find a house that looks like it might be hers?
うーん しかし 深追いも危険か
But that might be dangerous...
I guess I'll call it a day...
また あした尾行することにして
今日のところは引き揚げ…
...and retreat for now.
Shinonome Institute
It's completely obvious!
丸出しじゃないか！
I found it so suddenly!
いきなり見つかってしまった
Ever since project "Acquire Shinonome Nano" started,
これは東雲捕獲作戦
始まって以来の―
this could be the luckiest breakthrough.
ラッキーなんじゃないか？
I can't describe this with just "lucky".
いや これは
ラッキーなんて言葉じゃ計れない
It's more like...
何というか えーと
何だ えーと
Uh...
Well...
Um...
Whatever.
まあ いいか
This really fires me up.
なんだ このテンションの
上がりようは
ああ 今すぐにでも部屋に上がり
研究室を見たい
I just want to go in and see the laboratory.
I want to see the person who made Shinonome.
東雲を作った人を見たい
設計図を奪いたい
I want to steal the blueprints!
くっ　高鳴る期待に鼓動が
スタンピードしまくっている
With this climax, my heart is having a stampede!
Calm down, my cowboy!
落ち着け　私の中のカウボーイ
ビル･ワット
Bill Watt!
Since it's the person who created Shinonome,
なにせ 東雲を作った人の家
なんの仕掛けがあるか分からない
I don't know what kind of traps there'll be.
I shouldn't get too courageous.
血気の勇を戒めて かかるんだ
I'll just end with peeking today.
そうだ 今日のところは
のぞくだけで
Is there something you need?
（ビスケット２号）
何か ご用ですか？
What?!
（中村）ギニア！
Crap, a patrol robot already found me!
（中村）しまった
いきなり 偵察ロボに
見つかってしまった
It looks pretty cheap,
ずいぶんチープな外見だが―
but it was probably made by the same skilled person that made Shinonome.
こいつも東雲を作った
高い技術力の産物
I have no idea what might happen if something goes wrong.
ヘタをしたら
何されるか分からん
For now, I need to raise a white flag.
とりあえず
無抵抗をアピールせねば
Nakamura-sensei.
あっ 中村先生
Apparently you carried an injured lady, on your goat, all the way to the hospital.
Just as you say.
Could it be that you attend our school on your goat thinking ahead in the case something like this happened?
Don't tell me such a bad joke.
Now you were supposed to say "well said".
ギニア！
Here you go.
（なの）どうぞ
I was caught by surprise.
（中村）腰を抜かしてしまった
Because of that, I was able to gain entry,
そのおかげで
家に侵入できたのはいいが―
but I shouldn't forget about my objective.
完全アウェイということを
忘れてはならない
I think it's best to assume that there's a trap.
トラップがあると考えるのが
妥当だろう
For example, this tea.
例えば このお茶
It's perfectly sane to think that there's a drug in it that erases your memories.
一時的に記憶を消す薬が
入っているとみて間違いない
There's probably a camera watching me from somewhere in this roo-
それに この部屋も
どこに監視の目が
W-What is that?!
ななななな 何だあれは？
There has to be something wrong with that.
明らかにフォルムがおかしい
It feels like I'm in danger with that thing in my sight...
雑然と置かれているようで―
どこかしら私を狙っているような
気がしないでもない気もする
If I make one wrong move,
ヘタしたら これ…
I'll be taken out!
やられるぞ
ど… どうしたんですか？
Is there something wrong?
（中村）ああっ　いや すまん
何でもないです
Oh sorry, there's nothing wrong!
I drank it.
（中村）飲んじゃった
What have I done?
しまった　私としたことが
Was it too hot?
If I'm going to be taken out...
どうせ やられるなら
I shall say it directly.
（中村）単刀直入に言おう
えっ？ あっ はい
Oh, yes!
I came here to get to know you much more deeply!
私は東雲のことを
深く知るためにここに来たんだ！
If I can, I want to see the real you.
できるならば
本当のお前を見たい
（なの）ええっ！
（中村）ダメか？
Can I?
ああ あの いや それは
個人の自由だとは思うんですが―
Well, it's completely up to personal preference,
but I don't think it's normal for two girls to have that kind of relationship,
女の子どうしがつきあうのは
普通じゃないというか
and I think it's best to be normal for that!
やっぱりそういうのは
普通が一番いいっていうか
ボッ　バ… バカ 違う
断じて違う
Stupid, no!
Completely wrong!
What are you thinking about?
何考えてるんだ
恥ずかしいやつだな お前は
You're so embarrassing!
（なの）ああっ
すいません すいません
I'm sorry, I'm sorry!
What I want to know more deeply is...
私が深く知りたいと
言うのはだな
Nano...
（はかせ）なの
Professor.
（なの）あっ はかせ
（中村）ええっ！
Nano, we ran out of snacks.
Did she just say "Professor"?
（中村）今 “博士”って
言わなかったか？
No way. I must have misheard it!
いや いやいやいや
単に私の聞き違いだろう
Just leave it until tomorrow.
I can't imagine this kid making Shinonome.
まさか この子どもが
東雲を作ったなど考えられん
Who is this person?
Is this person a relative of Shinonome?
この子どもは東雲の身内？
もしかして 妹？
This is Nakamura-sensei from our school.
Possibly a younger sister?
Does that mean this kid is also a robot?
だとすると この子どももロボ？
Hello, I'm the professor.
こんにちは はかせです
なのを作りました
I made Nano.
Shoulder Block!
（中村）ショルダーブロック
Professor!
Made?
作った？ 東雲をこの子どもが？
Why did you say that?!
This kid made Shinonome?
It's just a greeting.
Hey!
（阪本）おい！
（中村）あっ
Do something about this!
（阪本）これなんとかしろ
（中村）ああ
（阪本）ガキが また
なんか やりやがった
The kid did something again!
A homunculus?!
ホムンクルス！
The patrol robot outside,
外の偵察ロボ
不気味なだるま
the creepy doll thing,
the child professor,
子どもの博士
東雲なの  ホムンクルス
Shinonome Nano...
...and now a homunculus?
I'll admit that it was a mistake to come here unprepared,
丸腰で のこのこ入ってきた
私に落ち度があるのは認めるが
この家 相当ヤバすぎる
but this is just insane.
Professor, what kind of knot did you use?
I need to escape and rethink my plan!
隙を突いて 早く逃げ
作戦を練り直すほかない
The impossible knot.
It isn't coming off yet?
But...
I'm terrified that thing is going to come attack me,
あいつが
襲ってくるんじゃないかって―
恐怖がまとわりついて
ヘタに動けん
so I can't move recklessly...
If I politely ask to leave...
素直に帰ります
などと言おうものなら
Then...
（中村）キューッ
So it comes to this...
（中村）かくなる上は…
May I go to the washroom?
トイレに行っていいですか？
Oh sure.
あっ はい　じゃあ案内
Well, I-
Wait.
（中村）いや
（なの）あっ？
If you just tell me the location, I can go there alone.
（中村）
場所だけ教えてもらえれば
１人で行ける
So in the end, you fell for it, Shinonome Nano.
まんまと引っ掛かったな
東雲なの
My escape was a success.
見事 脱出成功だ
I knew you would believe what I told you.
私は分かっていたぞ
お前が　私の言ったことを
そのまま うのみにすることを
That's right.
そう  お前の弱点は
その 人の良さ
Your weakness is your kindness towards people.
Next time we meet, I'll be the one putting up attacks.
次に来るときはこの場所で―
お前にアゲインストの風を
吹かしてやる
待っているがいい
As long as that weakness doesn't go away,
お前の その弱点が消えぬかぎり
私は何度でもよみがえる
I'll be back as many times as it takes!
Are you on your way home?
あっ おかえりですか？
Crap!
しまった
N-No, I was just asked to trim the lawn.
あっ いや なんだ あれだ
ちょっと 芝生の手入れを
頼まれてだな
Wha?!
Oh, hold on for a moment!
（ビスケット２号）
ああっ ちょっと待っててください
Oh no, I was caught!
（中村）いかん　バレた
They completely saw through the fact that I was trying to escape.
私が脱出しようとしていたことも
すべてお見通しというわけか
Geez.
クッソ　何だこれ？
体が… 体の自由が！
What is this?
The freedom of my body!
こっちです
Over here.
えっ？ でもトイレだったんじゃ
Wasn't she going to the toilet?
Huh?!
（なの）わあっ！ 何だこれ？
What is this?!
あっ はかせ
Professor!
This glue comes off with water, right?
この のりって
水で取れるんですよね？
If I get caught now, everything will be finished.
What?
（中村）
ここで捕獲されてしまったら
すべてが終わる
Water!
My hopes, my dreams!
私の野望が！ 生きがいが！
What?
Crap, I need to do something about this situation...
クッソッ
なんとかしてこの状況を…
I can't hear you...
Curse you, Shinonome Institute!
おのれ 東雲研究所！
Water, water!
First of all, someone...
とりあえず 誰か…
...someone, help me!
誰か…
助けてくれ！
Oh, I have that!
（みお）あっ それ私持ってるよ
Really?
（安中(あんなか)）
ホント？ じゃお願いしていい？
Could I borrow it, then?
Sure.
いいよ　今度 持ってくるね
I'll bring it next time.
You really never know what's going to happen.
（なの）
“何が起こるか分からない
それが野球だ”って…
That's what baseball is.
Is that it?
それだけですか？
（祐子）
うん　急に笑い出して
元気になったんだ
She started laughing and became cheerful.
（なの）無理に 明るくふるまって
いるんじゃないですかね
Maybe she's just forcing herself to act cheerful.
She was denied by her long-admired senpai.
ずっと 憧れていた先輩に
失恋したんですし
It's certainly possible to see it that way.
（祐子）そんなふうに
見えなくもなくもない
Are you sure?
（なの）どっちです？ それ
（みお）あっ
Yukko, did you forget your homework again?
ゆっこ また宿題忘れたの？
違う　違うよ
No, that's not it!
あっ でも宿題忘れたのはホント
But the part about forgetting homework is true.
Geez. Make up your mind...
どっちなのよ
The answer will be given after the commercial break!
（祐子）正解はＣＭのあとで
（みお）はあ？
Huh?
あっ 面白いです 相生さん
ねえ 水上(みなかみ)さん
That's hilarious, Aioi-san!
Right, Minakami-san?
Flemming?
フリミング？
Rap?
ラップ？
Naganohara-san,
（安中）長野原さん
ついでに お願いなんだけど
I actually have another favour...
なに？
What is it?
Aioi-san, isn't there anything?
（なの）
相生さん 何かありませんか？
長野原さんを元気づける方法
A way to cheer up Naganohara-san...
I wonder why they went home...
（みお）
なんで帰っちゃったんだろう？
I was going to go eat something with them...
せっかく ゆっこたちと
何か食べてこうかと思ってたのにな
What are you doing?!
何やってんの？
Congratulations!
（麻衣･なの･祐子）
おめでとうございます
Go ahead and give it a spin!
（祐子）福引きをどうぞ
What are you doing? You're Yukko, aren't you?
（みお）何やってるの？
ゆっこでしょ？
Huh? Who is that?
（祐子）
ゆっこ？ 誰ですか それ？
It's as clear as glass...
（みお）バレバレだって
なのちゃん ネジ見えてるし
I can see Nano-chan's key, too...
（なの）こ… これは
ロボ的なものではなく
This is nothing related to robots!
Either way, it's a rule that people who pass here must do this!
（祐子）とにかく ここ通った人は
福引きしなきゃいけない決まりなの
Come on!
ほら！ 早く早く
What?
なによ もう
わけ分かんないんだから
Geez.
I don't get it...
I just have to spin it?
回せばいいの？
Congratulations!
（祐子）おめでとうございまーす
（みお）うわっ うっ
Geez. That's loud.
なに？ うるさいな
Here, a special prize!
（祐子）はい　特別賞です
What is this?
何なの これ？
Just accept it!
（祐子）いいから受け取って
I always say that these things you do aren't very fun...
いつも言ってるじゃん
ゆっこのこういうの
あんまり面白くない…
Well, now that you've received it, off you go!
（祐子）はい
受け取ったら行った行った
Thank you!
（なの）ありがとうございました
（水上麻衣(まい)）副賞
Bonus prize.
彫りたて
Thanks.
ありがとう
（祐子･なの）わあっ うんっ
I remember Sasahara-senpai saying something like this...
（みお）
昔 笹原先輩が話していたのを
聞いたことがある
The daily life that we live is possibly...
日々 私たちが
過ごしている日常は―
実は奇跡の連続なのかも
しれない
...a string of miracles.
I think... No, I'm sure it must be like that.
多分 いや きっと
そうなんだと思う
Voucher to stay
friends for all eternity
Aioi
Shinonome
Minakami
All right!
（みお）
よーし！ 帰ってマンガ 描こうっと
I'll go home and draw some manga!
Love-Like
Damn it...
（みさと）まったく もう
Thanks to you, we got lost!
あんたのせいで
道に迷ったじゃない
Sorry about that.
すまんな　モバイルフォンで
調べてみるか
Let's find our way with my mobile telephone.
What's with that?
何 その西洋かぶれ
携帯って言いなさいよ
Just call it a cellphone!
ブッハッハッハッ
Hey, why are you watching 1seg?!
TL Note: 1seg - Mobile TV
ちょっと 何ワンセグ見てんのよ
Don't you watch 1seg, too, Tachibana Misato?
立花みさとも
ワンセグを見ればいいではないか
あ！ 私のは ノンセグよ！
Mine is a NoSeg!
（なのちゃんのネジ）
なのちゃんのネジです
I'm Nano-chan's key!
Sometimes I turn!
たまに回ります
たまに止まります
Sometimes I don't!
Sometimes I come off!
たまに抜けます
そんな日々です
Those are my days!
The next episode of Nichijou is the last one!
次回の「日常」は
最終回
Narration:     Yokozawa Keiko
Look forward to it!
お楽しみに